<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-23T03:38:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Atlas of Extractive Complexity</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">EU Conflict Minerals Regulation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/eu-conflict-minerals" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EU Conflict Minerals Regulation" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/eu-conflict-minerals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/eu-conflict-minerals">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increase supply chain transparency and ensure the responsible sourcing of tin, tantalum, tungsten and gold, largely mined in places that suffer from armed conflict and where human rights violations are widespread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Union importers and smelters of tin, tungsten, tantalum and gold in “conflict-affected” or “high-risk” countries or areas must conduct due-diligence after the OECD 5-step framework.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ResponsibleSteel Assurance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resp-steel" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ResponsibleSteel Assurance" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resp-steel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resp-steel">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard is voluntary and applies to operational steelmaking sites and to related sites that process raw materials for steelmaking, or that produce steel product - not to service providers, mine sites, or to sites producing final products. It comprises 12 principles for the responsible sourcing and production that cover sustainability issues at large. Policies can be developed at the group/corporate owner level, and not necessarily at the site level, but third party auditing verifies implementation until sites (both mines for raw material and scrap) upon which a certification decision is taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Policies can be developed at the group/corporate owner level, and not necessarily at the site level, but third-party auditing verifies implementation until sites (both mines for raw material and scrap) upon which a certification decision is taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;not publicly available&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="labour," /><category term="conflict" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Provenance Proof Initiative</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ppi-ggl" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Provenance Proof Initiative" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ppi-ggl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ppi-ggl">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative seeks to bring more transparency and traceability to every step in the gemstone industry’s value chain. It supplements inclusions-based identification of regional origin with mines’ information encoded in nano-sized particules, and uses blockchain to securely store, record and share all operations from mine to lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;not publicly available&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="traceability" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maendeleo Diamond Standards certification</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/maendeleo-cert" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maendeleo Diamond Standards certification" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/maendeleo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/maendeleo-cert">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standards adapt and implement existing responsible sourcing protocols and standards of industrial diamond mining to artisanal and small-scale operators to build a bridge between this sector and existing responsible supply chains. MDS certification focuses on Kimberley Process-approved zones and formalized operations. It includes due-dilligence, traceability and segregation policies and procedures for buyers. Certification is granted upon third party auditing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certification is granted on a mine site basis upon third party auditing that includes conformance to due-diligence, traceability and segregation policies and procedures for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;not publicly available&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="conflict," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CIBJO Responsible Sourcing Guidance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cibjo-resp" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CIBJO Responsible Sourcing Guidance" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cibjo-resp-source</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cibjo-resp">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guidance standardizes how jewellery and gemstone firms should implement supply-chain due diligence. It follows the framework of the OECD Guidance, the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme and requires compliance to the World Diamond Council System of Warranties Guidelines for diamonds (i.e. extension of KPC compliance to polished diamonds).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict," /><category term="labor" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trustchain (Pilot)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trustchain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trustchain (Pilot)" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trustchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trustchain">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking and authentication system covering all stages of the supply chain, and using both digital certification and third party audit for diamonds and gold produced against responsible standards.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="traceability" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RMI’s Blockchain Guidelines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rmi-blockchain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RMI's Blockchain Guidelines" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rmi-blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rmi-blockchain">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guidelines apply to any mineral or metal supply chain with a goal to define the terms, concepts and fundamental data attributes required to identify supply chain actors that participate in a blockchain-based solution, with a focus on principles for interoperability between different chain-of-custody solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRMA Standard for Responsible Mining</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/irma-cert" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRMA Standard for Responsible Mining" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/irma-cert</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/irma-cert">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRMA’s Standard defines good practices for what responsible mining should look like at the industrial-scale mine site level (business integrity, planning, social responsibility, environmental responsibility) that independent auditors will use as the benchmark for responsible mines. IRMA offers third-party certification of industrial-scale mine sites for all mined materials that is governed equitably by the private sector, local communities, civil society, and workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRMA certification is based on third-party auditing of industrial-scale mine sites; the scope of the audit depends on the life stage of the mine. Besides certification, IRMA issues lower “verified level achievements”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carrizal (Zimapán) Mine, Mexico, by CARRIZAL MINING S.A. DE C.V., Mexico; Unki Mines, Zimbabwe, by Anglo American, London, UK&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="conflict," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gemfair (Pilot)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gemfair-debeers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gemfair (Pilot)" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gemfair-debeers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gemfair-debeers">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certification mechanisms aiming to create market routes for artisanally mined diamonds by implementing due diligence standards and digitally ensuring the traceability of diamonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formalized artisanal mine site operate in conformity with OECD and Maendeleo standards and engage in continuous improvement as adapted from the CRAFT code. Diamonds produced by certified members are sealed and tagged to enable full digital chain of custody, with the aim of using blockchain to secure documentation and transactions. Applicants are certified based of self-assessment, secondary audit by Gemfair, and third-party audit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="conflict," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CRAFT code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/craft-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRAFT code" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/craft-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/craft-code">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRAFT is a tool that facilitates the comprehension, application, and commitment to due diligence by all stakeholders in artisanal supply chains. It enables the identification and mitigation of risks existing in the artisanal and small-scale mining (ASM) sector, and supports progressive improvement in environmental and social performance. It aims to facilitate ASM products to access formal supply chains and possibly apply for an external certification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants to a CRAFT scheme must produce CRAFT report along the OECD framework implemented in CRAFT’s performance indicators. CRAFT Schemes have no obligation to carry out any due diligence or verification of the content of CRAFT Reports, but can use them for certification by other schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not publicly available (at pilot stage)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="labor," /><category term="conflict" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry></feed>