<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-22T12:53:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Atlas of Extractive Complexity</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">EU Conflict Minerals Regulation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/eu-conflict-minerals" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EU Conflict Minerals Regulation" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/eu-conflict-minerals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/eu-conflict-minerals">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increase supply chain transparency and ensure the responsible sourcing of tin, tantalum, tungsten and gold, largely mined in places that suffer from armed conflict and where human rights violations are widespread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Union importers and smelters of tin, tungsten, tantalum and gold in “conflict-affected” or “high-risk” countries or areas must conduct due-diligence after the OECD 5-step framework.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CIBJO Responsible Sourcing Guidance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cibjo-resp" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CIBJO Responsible Sourcing Guidance" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cibjo-resp-source</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cibjo-resp">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guidance standardizes how jewellery and gemstone firms should implement supply-chain due diligence. It follows the framework of the OECD Guidance, the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme and requires compliance to the World Diamond Council System of Warranties Guidelines for diamonds (i.e. extension of KPC compliance to polished diamonds).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict," /><category term="labor" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RMI’s Blockchain Guidelines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rmi-blockchain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RMI's Blockchain Guidelines" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rmi-blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rmi-blockchain">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guidelines apply to any mineral or metal supply chain with a goal to define the terms, concepts and fundamental data attributes required to identify supply chain actors that participate in a blockchain-based solution, with a focus on principles for interoperability between different chain-of-custody solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CRAFT code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/craft-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRAFT code" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/craft-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/craft-code">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRAFT is a tool that facilitates the comprehension, application, and commitment to due diligence by all stakeholders in artisanal supply chains. It enables the identification and mitigation of risks existing in the artisanal and small-scale mining (ASM) sector, and supports progressive improvement in environmental and social performance. It aims to facilitate ASM products to access formal supply chains and possibly apply for an external certification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants to a CRAFT scheme must produce CRAFT report along the OECD framework implemented in CRAFT’s performance indicators. CRAFT Schemes have no obligation to carry out any due diligence or verification of the content of CRAFT Reports, but can use them for certification by other schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not publicly available (at pilot stage)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="labor," /><category term="conflict" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Responsible Mining Index</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rmi-index" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Responsible Mining Index" /><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rmi-index</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rmi-index">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voluntary evidence-based assessment of large-scale mining companies’ policies and practices, both at corporate and mine-site level, on a range of economic, environmental, social and governance (EESG) issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None.  The assessment is based on publicly available information on the companies and their mine sites by RMI; companies are invited to complete missing information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anglo American, London, UK; AngloGold Ashanti, Johannesburg, South Africa; Antofagasta PLC, London, UK; ArcelorMittal, Luxembourg, Luxembourg; Banpu, Bangkok, Thailand; Barrick Gold Corp, oronto, Canada; BHP, Melbourne, Australia; Buenaventura, Lima, Peru; Bumi Resources, Jakarta, Indonesia; China Shenhua, Beijing, China; Coal India, Calcutta, India; Codelco, Santiago, Chile; Eurasian Resources Group (ERG), Luxembourg, Luxembourg; Evraz, Moscow, Russia; Exxaro Resources, Gauteng, Afrique du Sud; First Quantum Minerals, Vancouver, Canada; Fortescue, Perth, Australia; Freeport-McMoRan, Phoenix, USA; Glencore, Baar, Switzerland; Gold Fields, Johannesburg, South Africa; Grupo México; Mexico D.F., Mexico; Industrias Peñoles, Durango, Mexico; MMG, Melbourne, Australia; Navoi MMC, Navoi, Uzbekistan; Newcrest Mining, Melbourne, Australia; Newmont, Denver, USA; NMDC, Hyderabad, India; Nordgold, Moscow, Russia; Orano, Châtillon, France; Peabody Energy, Chicago, USA; Polymetal, Limassol, Cyprus; Rio Tinto, London, UK; RUSAL, Moscow, Russia; Sibanye-Stillwater, Sibanye-Stillwater, Johannesburg, South Africa; Teck Resources, Vancouver, Canada; Vale, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Vedanta Resources, London, UK; Zijin, Xiamen, China. –&amp;gt; List and locations of all 1054 related mine sites available on xlsx here: https://2020.responsibleminingindex.org/en/raw-data&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chinese Due Diligence Guidelines for Responsible Mineral Supply Chains</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chinese-dd" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chinese Due Diligence Guidelines for Responsible Mineral Supply Chains" /><published>2015-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chinese-dd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chinese-dd">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Guidance provides a 5-step framework to identify, (2) assess and (3) mitigate human rights risks, as well as recommendations for (4) third party auditing and (5) reporting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bettercoal code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bettercoal-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bettercoal code" /><published>2013-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bettercoal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bettercoal-code">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating set of health, safety, social and environmental standards for coal producers against which their performance is assessed to jointly develop a continuous improvement plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bettercoal members conduct self-assessment (1-2 years) and undergo a third party assessment (1-5 years) of their performance against the twelve principles of the Bettercoal Code. Assessment does not provide a certification of performance but instead drives a model of continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppliers: Canyon Coal Pty (Ltd), Johannesburg, South Africa; Cerrejón Coal Company, La Guajira, Colombia; Consol Pennsylvania Coal Company, Cecil Township, U.S.A; Drummond company Inc. Itochu Corp., Birmingham, USA; Foresight Energy, St. Louis, USA; HJ Banks &amp;amp; co. ltd, Durham, UK; Kangra Coal (Pty) ltd, Ogies, South Africa; KTK Overseas, Kemerovo, Russia; Kuzbassrazrezugol Coal Company OJSC, Kemerovo, Russia; Maikuben-West LLP, Pavolodar, Kazakhstan; C.I. Prodeco S.A., Barranquilla, Colombia; PT Adaro Indonesia, Jakarta , Indonesia; PT Bayan Resources, Jakarta, Indonesia; PT Bhumi Rantau Energi, Jakarta, Indonesia; RWE Power AG, Essen, Germany; Siberian Business Union Coal, Kemerovo, Russia; SUEK JSC, Moscow, Russia; Taldinskaya Mining Company LLC, Moscow, Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members (Buyers): EDP, Lisbon, Portugal; EnBW Energie Baden-Württemberg AG, Karlsruhe, Germany; Enel SpA, Roma, Italy; ESB (Electricity Supply Board), Dublin, Ireland; Fortum, Espoo, Finland; Grosskraftwerk Mannheim AG, Manheim, Germany; JERA Global Markets, Tokyo, Japan; Onyx Power, Berlin, Germany; Ørsted A/S, Fredericia, Denmark; RWE AG, Essen, Germany; Vattenfall, Solna, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Better Gold Initiative</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/better-gold-Swiss" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Better Gold Initiative" /><published>2013-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/better-gold-swiss</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/better-gold-Swiss">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created by Swiss players of the gold value chain, from refiners to retailers, BGI aims to create a market driven mechanism (based on purchases with a premium) that enables formalized artisanal gold mining entities to adopt more socially inclusive and better environmental practices through technical assistance and impact assessment financed as part of members’ CSR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upstream members must operate in legality and comply with purchasers Due Diligence requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A.Favre et Fils, Geneva, Switzerland; Argor Heraeus SA, Mendrisio, Switzerland; Audemars Piguet, Le Brassus, Switzerland; Breitling, Granges, Switzerland; Cartier (Richemont SA), Geneva, Switzerland; Chopard, Meyrin, Switzerland; Fondation Haute Horlogerie, Geneva, Switzerland; Fredy Sadik SA, Lausanne, Switzerland; Helveticor, DIetikon, Switzerland; Imagination &amp;amp; Swiss Creative Lab, Zug, Switzerland; Julius Bär, Zürich, Switzerland; Metalor; PAMP, Castel San Pietro, Switzerland; PX Group, La Chaux de Fond, Switzerland; QORE, Geneva, Switzerland; Raiffeisen, St-Gallen, Switzerland; UBS, Zürich, Switzerland; Valcambi, Balerna, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="environment," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WGC Conflict-Free Gold Standard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wgc-gold-standard" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WGC Conflict-Free Gold Standard" /><published>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wgc-gold</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wgc-gold-standard">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Standard aims to help gold producers to demonstrate that their gold has been extracted in a manner that does not fuel conflict or the abuse of human rights associated with such conflicts by operationalising the OECD guidance at the level of mines. Conformance with the standard is externally assured and is not a prerequisite for WGC membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conformance with the standard is externally assured but is not a prerequisite for WGC membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agnico-Eagle Mines, Toronto, Canada; Alamos Gold, Toronto, Canada; AngloGold Ashanti, Johannesbourg, South Africa; Aura minerals, Miami, Florida; Barrick, Toronto, Canada; Compania de Minas Buenaventura, Lima, Peru; B2Gold, Vancouver, Canada; Calibre Mining, Vancouver, Canada; Centerra, Toronto, Canada; China National Gold Corporation, Beijing, China; Eldorado Gold, Vancouver, Canada; Endeavour Mining Corporation, Vancouver, Canada; Equinox Gold, Vancouver, Canada; Franco-Nevada Corporation, Toronto, Canada; Golden Star Resources, Toronto, Canada; Hummingbird Resources, London, UK; IAMGOLD, Toronto, Canada; Kinross Gold, Toronto, Canada; Kirkland Lake Gold, Toronto, Canada; Newcrest, Melbourne, Australia; Newmont, Denver, USA; OceanaGold, Melbourne, Australia; Pretivm, Vancouver, Canada; Resolute, Perth, Australia; Royal Gold, Denver, USA; Sandstorm Gold Royalties, Vancouver, Canada; Shandong Gold Group, Jinan, China; Shandong Zhaojin Group, Zhaoyuan, China; Sibanye-Stillwater, Johanesburg, South Africa; Torex Gold Resources, Toronto, Canada; Wheaton Precious Metals, Vancouver, Canada; Yamana Gold, Toronto, Canada; Zijin Mining Group, Xiamen, CHina. –&amp;gt; updated map of members’ productive mines https://www.gold.org/who-we-are/our-members&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RJC Chain-of-custody (CoC) certification</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rjc-coc-cert" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RJC Chain-of-custody (CoC) certification" /><published>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rjc-coc-cert</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rjc-coc-cert">&lt;h3&gt;Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RJC CoC is voluntary to RJC members and certifies that mined and recycled material is traced and segregated along the supply chain, and that it meets eligibility criteria of responsible sourcing, optionally claims of provenance. It implements the OECD guidance to the jewellery supply chains and applies to precious metals. CoC certification requires third-party auditing at every stage of the supply chain upon which a certification decision is taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoC certification requires third-party auditing at every stage of the supply chain and surveillance audit within 12-18 months upon which a certification decision is taken. Recertification occurs every 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Member Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8853 SPA, Pero (MI), Italia; ABProduct Sarl, La Chaux-De-Fonds, Switzerland; Albascan, Johannesburg, South Africa; Allgemeine Gold – und Silberscheideanstalt AG, Pforzhein, Germany; Altmann Casting AG, Ipsach, Switzerland; Arezzo Refinery Co., Tungunsukla, Thailand; Argentoro 1965 S.R.L,  Valenza, Italy; Argor-Heraeus SA, Mendrisio, Switzerland; Atelier Bleu Platine, Paris, France; AU Traders and Refiners (Pty) Ltd, Johannesbourg, South Africa; Audemars Piguet SA, Le Brassus, Switzerland; Aurum Metals (PTY) LTD, Springs, South Africa; B &amp;amp; C Srl Uninominale, Valenza, Italia; Balduzzi Microfusioni Srl, Valenza, Italy; Baud Industries, Les Verrières, Switzerland; Bauer-Walser AG, Pforzhein, Germany; BD Product, Mamirolle, France; Beauregard Manufacture SA, La Chaux.de -Fonds, Switzerland; Beauregard Sarl, Couteuges, France; Best Buy Products Inc., New York, USA; BIGBAG srl, Valenza, Italy; Blandenier SA, Geneva, Switzerland; BLS S.p.A., Camisano Vicentino, Italy; BOTECCHI IVO SRL, Valenza, Ital; Boucledor SA, Meyrin, Switzerland; Bulgari S.p.A., Rome, Italy; Buzio Snc di Buzio Massimiliano &amp;amp; C., Rampazzo, Italy; C. Hafner GmbH &amp;amp; Co. KG, Wimsheim, Germany; Callegaro F.lli snc, Valenza, Italy; Cape Precious Metals, Cape Town, South Africa; CAPSA Camille Piquerez SA, La Neuveville, Switzerland; Carlo Luca della Quercia Srl, Valenza, Italy; Cendres+Métaux Holding SA, Biel, Switzerland; C.G.S. SRL, Valenza, Italy; Chimet S.P.A, Val Di Chiana, Italy; Chrysos SPA,  Vicenza, Italy; COOKSON MÉTAUX PRÉCIEUX, Paris, France; Cookson Precious Metals - Cooksongold, Birmingham, UK; Coringer, Paris, France; Costa Team Srl, Valenza, Italy; COSTANZO E RIZZETTO SRL, Valenza, Italy; CROVA.LAB S.R.L, Valenza, Italy; Cyberis SA, Glovelier , Switzerland; Diatheke SA, Geneva, Switzerland; DUHEM, Paris, France; Euroshine Jewellery Works, Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai, India; Facet Jewellery Solutions, S.L, Barcelona, Spain; Fiedler SA, Geneva, Switzerland; Fimm SA, Porentruy, Switzerland; Freschi &amp;amp; Vangelisti Srl, Arezzo, Italy; Gauta Refineries (Pty) Ltd, Boksburg, South Africa; GEBA Precious Metals Pty Ltd, Pretoria, South Africa; Goldec SA, La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland; Grassano S.R.L, Valenza, Italy; Gucci, Scandicci, Italy; Hamard-Vitau, Paris, France; Heraeus Limited, Fanling, Hong Kong; Hermann Staib GmbH, Pforzheim, Germany; H. Hilderbrand et Cie SA, Geneva, Switzerland; Historic Originals Limited, Reading, UK; HTL SRL, Castel Maggiore, Italy; Hybrid Diamonds &amp;amp; Gold Pty Ltd, Germiston, South Africa; I Fanton SRL, Vicenza, Italy; I.M.O. SRL, Vicenza, Italy; Isabella Jewellers CC, Germiston, South Africa; Italpreziosi S.p.A., Arezzo, Italy; IVIERRE SRL, Valenza, Italy; IWC Schaffhausen, Branch of Richemont SA, Schaffhausen, Switzerland; JMB Créations Sarl, Geneva, Switzerland; Rio Tinto Kennecott Utah Copper LLC, Utah, USA; Kusasa Refining Pty Ltd, Wadeville, South Africa; La Banchetta Srl – Operatori Professionali in Oro, Valenza, Italy; LAC S.p.A, Romano D’Ezzelino, Italy; Legor Group S.p.A., Bressanvido, Italy; Lingotto Srl, Valenza, Italy; LOSANGE, Besançon, France; Louis Lang SA, Porrentruy, Switzerland; Marinegold PTY LTD, Cape Town, South Africa; Mattioli S.p.A, Torino, Italy; Metal Concentrators SA Pty, Cape Town, South Africa; Metalem SA, Le Locle, Switzerland; Metalor Technologies SA, Neuchatel, Switzerland; Metaltech srl, Monticello, Italy; Metaux Precieux France, Paris, France; MI.VA. SRL, Valenza, Italy; MIL’OR DI CARRARO ALESSANDRO &amp;amp; C. SNC, Valenza, Italy; Millennium International Alloys Pty Ltd, Johannesburg, South Africa; Minuzzo Gioielli SRL, Valenza, Italy; Nakagawa Corporation, Tokyo, Japan; Natural Precious Metals Pty Ltd, Durban, South Africa; Nivarox-FAR SA, Le Locle, Switzerland; Novart S.R.L., Arezzo, Italy; Nuovi Gioielli Srl, Mussolente, Italy; Orest Group, Erstein, France; Orline, Chabeuil, France; ORO TREND SRL, Valenza, Italy; OTELINE, Rillieux-La-Pape, France; PAMP S.A., Castel San Pietro, Switzerland; Pandora Alloys Srl, Milan, Italy; Patros Srl, Vicenza, Italy; Pesavento SRL Unipersonale, Vicenza, Italy; Pibor Iso SA, Glovelier, Switzerland; POURQUERY DMP Lyon, France; Procadrans, branch of Richemont International SA, Porrentruy, Switzerland ; Progold SPA, Vicenza, Italy; Promotion SpA, Vicentina, Italy; PX Precinox SA, La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland; Quadrance &amp;amp; Habillage SA, La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland; Raselli Franco s.p.a., Valenza, Italy; RGS SRL, Vicenza, Italy; Roberto Demeglio SpA, Valenza, Italy; Rolot et Lemasson, Beaune, France; S.A. Precious Metals (Pty) Ltd, Gauteng, South Africa; SAAMP, Limonest, France; SAFIMET SPA, Arezzo, Italy; Salanitro SA, Geneva, Switzerland; SEMPSA JP SA, Madrid, Spain; Skomboys Refineries, Cape Town, South Africa; Sopafonte, Paris, France; STILNOVO SRL, Montferrato, Italy; Swissmec SA, Moutier, Switzerland; TCA SPA, Capolona, Italy; Technis SRL, Sesto Calende, Italy; TOMEI SRL, APRILIA, Italy; TRE PI Srl, Rome, Italy; Treemme SPA Unipersonale, Arezzo, Italy; U-Man Watches Sarl, Geneva, Switzerland; UNOAERRE INDUSTRIES SPA, AREZZO, Italy; Valcambi sa, Balerna, Switzerland; Valmet SRL, Calenzano, Italy; Valyon, Brignais, France; Varinor SA, Delémont, Switzerland; Viquodeco SARL, Delémont, Switzerland; VPA SpA, Valmadonna, Italy; Wieland Edelmetalle GmbH, Pforzheim, Germany; World Ring Co. Ltd., Tokyo, Japan; Zion Precious Metals (Pty) Ltd, Germiston, South Africa,&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="conflict," /><category term="labour" /><summary type="html">Description:</summary></entry></feed>